Jessie Lloyd O'Connor Papers, 1850-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES 1918-1988
  - Women's Work, Women's Health (Conference)1980 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Women's World Congress For Peace and Liberty1939 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Woolman Hill1958-66 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Worker's Defense League1938-74, undated (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Worker's Music League1932-35, undated (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - World Affairs Council of Rhode Island1948-55 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - World Assembly For Peace1951-69 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - World Association of World Federalists1959-87 (Box 134, Folder 9)
  - World Constitution and Parliament Association1968-82 (Box 134, Folder 10)
  - World Constitution Coordinating Committeeundated (Box 134, Folder 11)
  - World Council For The People's World Convention1952-56 (Box 134, Folder 12)
  - World Council Of Churches1954 (Box 134, Folder 13)
  - World Events Committee1945-49, undated (Box 134, Folder 14)
  - World Federalist Youth1970, undated (Box 134, Folder 15)
  - World Federalists of Tarrant County1946-48 (Box 134, Folder 16)
  - World Fellowship, Inc.
    - Correspondence and printed material1940-83, undated (Box 134, Folder 17)
    - World Fellowship News1954-70 (Box 134, Folder 18)
  - World Government of World Citizens1986 (Box 134, Folder 19)
  - World Movement For World Federal Government1950 (Box 134, Folder 20)
  - World Peace Commission1946 (Box 134, Folder 21)
  - World Peace News
    [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES --Wynner, Edith]
    - Publication1975-86 (Box 134, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and miscellaneous1975-88, undated (Box 134, Folder 23)
  - World People's Consultative Assembly1950, undated (Box 134, Folder 24)
  - W1933-83, undated (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Young Women's Christian Association1924-72, undated (Box 135, Folder 2)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates--Dieckmann, Annetta]
  - Youth Against War and Fascism1966-77 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Yugoslav Information Center1949-52, undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Y1946-64, undated (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - Lists of names connected with various organizations1929-33, 1950, undated (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous notesundated (Box 135, Folder 7)
- SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES 1893-1988
  - Anti-Communism1936-68, undated (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Appalachia1969-70, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
    [see also West, Don and Hedy; and SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-West, Don]
  - Bloor, Ella Reeve1935-36, [1951?], undated (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Book and magazine subscription offers1893, 1942-82, undated (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Boudin, Leonard and Kathy (daughter)1962, 1983, 1989 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Braden, Anne and Carl1955-88, undated (Box 136, Folder 6)
    [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Southern Leadership Conference Fund]
  - Bridges, Harry1941-42 (Box 136, Folder 7)
    [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges]
  - Browder, Earl1938-41, undated (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Bryant, Louise Stevens1969 (Box 136, Folder 9)
  - Carr, Charlotte1956 (Box 136, Folder 10)
  - Cayce, Edgar (Box 136)
    [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Association for Research and Enlightenment]
  - Children/youth1939-66, undated (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - China1937, 1956, 1967-78 (Box 136, Folder 12)
  - Civil liberties1937-86, undated (Box 136, Folder 13)
  - Civil rights1928-79, undated (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Close, Upton1946, undated (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Cold War1951-circa 1960, undated (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Consumer Information1937-52, undated (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Cooperatives
    - General1925-81, undated (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Bread and Butter newsletter1941-44 (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Little Compton (RI) Food Co-op1981-82, undated (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - North Shore Co-operative Society (Chicago)1939-44, undated (Box 137, Folder 8)
  - Cuba1957-70 (Box 137, Folder 9)
  - Dance (Box 137)
    [see Music]
  - Davis, Angela1971-72 (Box 137, Folder 10)
  - Davis, Marian Rubins1978-82, undated (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Day, Bonnie1956-73, undated (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Dies Committee1939-43, undated (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Economics1925-75, undated (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Educationcirca 1937-68, undated (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Eisler, Hans1935-36, 1967, 1981, undated (Box 138, Folder 6)
    [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--National Committee to Aid Victims of German Fascism, 1933-34, n.d.]
  - Environment1955-88 (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Ford Peace Expedition (Box 138)
    [see SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates--Fussell, Paul, and SERIES III. WRITINGS--Articles and essays-Alphabetical--"The Story of the Ford Peace Ship"]
  - Graves, Anna Melissa, 1937circa 1950, undated (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Haag, Sofia and Charles1956, 1975, undated (Box 138, Folder 9)
  - Haessler, Carl1972 (Box 138, Folder 10)
  - Health1938-77, undated (Box 138, Folder 11)
  - Hennacy, Ammon1959-70, undated (Box 138, Folder 12)
  - Housing1937-63, undated (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Illinois/Chicago1937-57, undated (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - In Fact newsletter1943-50 (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - India1906-1944, undated (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - International affairs1935-70, undated (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Japan1937-50, undated (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Karolyi, Catherine1918, undated (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - Kinhaven1954-83, undated (Box 139, Folder 8)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Friends and associates--Dushkin, Dorothy and David; and General/business-Children-Schools and camps-Kinhaven]
  - Korean War1951-52, undated (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - Labor
    - 1930-59 (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - 1960-79, undated (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Lamont, Corliss and Helen1960, 1972, 1981, undated (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - Little Compton, RI1952-82, undated (Box 140, Folder 3)
  - Luscomb, Florence1953-57, undated (Box 140, Folder 4)
  - Mason, Maryundated (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - McCarthy, Joseph1951 (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Music
    [see also Eisler, Hans, Reynolds, Malvina, Robinson, Earl, and Wells, Jenny; SERIES III. WRITINGS -Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject-Music and dance]
    - General1932-82, undated (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Dance1950-81, undated (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Newport Folk Festival1959-65 (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - People's Songs1946-49, undated (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Songs
      - General1911-84, undated (Box 140, Folder 11-12)
      - Labor1933-49, undated (Box 141, Folder 1)
      - Political1950-88, undated (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Songs of the American Peoplecirca 1939 (Box 141, Folder 3)
  - Nearing, Scott1944-82, undated (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - New Deal1936-41 (Box 141, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Weapons/Disarmament1945-82 (Box 141, Folder 6)
  - Olivereau, Louise (Box 141)
    [see SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Friends and associates---Jarrett, Sally, and Pollard, Jennie O.; and SERIES III. WRITINGS-Revolution in Seattle]
  - Peace
    - General1942-80, undated (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Articles/Statements1936-72, undated (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Events/Conferences1938-80, undated (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters/Pamphlets1924-82, undated (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Poemscirca 1950-54, undated (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - People, A-Z (Box 142, Folder 3)
  - Poland1948-52, undated (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - Political campaigns
    [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS--Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject- Wallace, Henry; and SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Progressive Party]
    - General1935-76, undated (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Douglas, William O.1952 (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Holdridge, Herbert1952-54, undated (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Illinois1940-70, undated (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - LaFollette, Robertcirca 1924 (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Massachusetts1952-83, undated (Box 142, Folder 10)
    - McCarthy, Eugene1960-68 (Box 142, Folder 11)
    - McGovern, George1970-72, undated (Box 142, Folder 12)
    - Perry, Albertcirca 1967 (Box 142, Folder 13)
    - Rhode Island1948-82, undated (Box 142, Folder 14)
    - Socialist parties1958-68, undated (Box 142, Folder 15)
    - Texas1944-62 (Box 142, Folder 16)
  - Political prisoners and refugees
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates-Boschan, Paul, and Papaandreu, Eulalia Figuieredo]; and SERIES IV. ORGANIZATIONS-- Emergency Committee to Save the Jewish People of Europe]
    - General1939-59 (Box 142, Folder 17)
    - Boschan, Paul1939-62, undated (Box 142, Folder 18)
    - Papaandreu, Eulalia Figuieredo1951-54 (Box 142, Folder 19)
  - Religion1938-82, undated (Box 143, Folder 1-2)
  - Reynolds, Malvina1959-80, undated (Box 143, Folder 3)
  - Robinson, Earl1941-88, undated (Box 143, Folder 4)
    [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS -Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject-Robinson, Earl; and SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-Earl Robinson Foundation]
  - Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel1952-63, undated (Box 143, Folder 5)
    [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS -Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject- Rosenberg, Julius and Ethel]
  - Russia/U.S.S.R.1936-60, undated (Box 143, Folder 6)
    [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Russia]
  - Sargent Bulletin (newsletter)1939-40 (Box 143, Folder 7)
  - Schwimmer-Lloyd Collection (New York Public Library) (Box 143, Folder 8)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--General/business-Libraries and archives-New York Public Library]
  - Schwimmer, Rosika and Franciska1924-86, undated (Box 143, Folder 9)
  - Seeger, Pete1948-88, undated (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - Serafini, Sula Wing and Enzo1939-80, undated (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Shelley, Rebecca1949-61, undated (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Silva Mind Control1972-75, undated (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Gerald1946-65, undated (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Louise Pettibone1962 (Box 144, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Civil War1938-39, 1966, undated (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Strong, Anna Louise1951-79, undated (Box 144, Folder 8)
    [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject- Russia-Moscow Daily News]
  - Szilard, Leo1953-64 (Box 144, Folder 9)
  - Theater1925-67, undated (Box 144, Folder 10)
  - Thomas, Caroline Bedell1944-88 (Box 144, Folder 11)
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra1941, 1948, 1979 (Box 144, Folder 12)
  - Travel1924-68 (Box 144, Folder 13)
  - United Nations1945-70 (Box 144, Folder 14)
  - Universal Military Training1944-52 (Box 144, Folder 15)
  - Vietnam War1958-73, undated (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Ward, Harry1938, undated (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Wells, Jenny1947-48, undated (Box 145, Folder 3)
    [see also Music]
  - West, Don and Hedy1947-84, undated (Box 145, Folder 4)
    [see also Appalachia]
  - Williams, Claude (includes audiotapes of memorial service)1942-79, undated (Box 145, Folder 5)
    [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-Claude Williams Support Committee]
  - Winnetka Power Plant1956-57, undated (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Women1917-80, undated (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - World Government1942-70, undated (Box 145, Folder 8)
  - World War II1931-45, undated (Box 145, Folder 9)
  - Wynner, Edith1944-80, undated (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
    [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--World Peace News]
  - Yeomans, Andrew1954, undated (Box 146, Folder 3)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Correspondence: Carol Bedell Thomas (article re: cancer research); Seeger family Christmas Card, 1951, 1978 (Box 147)
  - Biographical material
    - Article in Providence Sunday Journal Magazine8 Feb 1981 (Box 147)
    - Calendars1985-88 (Box 147)
    - Diplomas: church school and Smith College1920, 1925 (Box 147)
    - Rhode Island House of Representative resolution re: JLO's death1989 (Box 147)
    - Map of Maverick ranch (Box 147)
    - Bumper sticker (Box 147)
    - Photographs: album of European trip, 1926; miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 147)
  - Writings-research material
    - Printed material in Russian1927, 1929, 1937, 1950, undated (Box 147)
    - Federated Press poster (Box 147)
    - Posters from Harlan, KY1931, undated (Box 147)
    - "It's Hard" - musical scoreAugust 1944 (Box 147)
  - Organizations
    - Abraham Lincoln School: Advertisement1944 (Box 147)
    - National CIO Committee to Abolish Discrimination: poster - "I Start Work Today" undated (Box 147)
    - National Committee to Win Amnesty for the Smith Act Victims: "Amnesty posterundated (Box 147)
    - Progressive Party: flier, circa 1951, and newspaper advertisement27 May 1952 (Box 147)
    - Women Strike for Peace, NYT advertisement1980 (Box 147)
    - National Committee for Repeal of the McCarran Act: postercirca 1964 (Box 147)
    - SANE (National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy: posters, 1957, 1958, 1959; NYT advertisements, 1960, 1969 (Box 147)
    - United World Federalists: poster, "World Congress of World Federalists" 1956 (Box 147)
    - World Constitution Coordinating Committee: posterundated (Box 147)
  - Subject files-political campaigns
    - "This 1928 Campaign in Cartoons" by Art Young (Box 147)
    - Newspapers and other printed material re: peace, Russia, strikes, Spanish Civil War, Vietnam war, and Claude Williams (Box 147)
    - Tempe Daily News: advertisements1958 (Box 147)
    - Scrapbook "organized" by friend of J. L. O'Connor celebrating opening of the U. N. in 1945undated (Box 148)
  - Biographical material-homes: blueprints and maps of Little Compton estate (1950) and Lloyd estate, Sakonnet Point (1911?) (Map-case Flat File)
  - Writings: Moscow Daily News and other newspapers in Russian1933, undated (Map-case Flat File)
  - Memorabilia: posters (mostly in Russian) (Map-case Flat File)
  - Subject files: newspaper advertisement - anti-HUAC petitioncirca 1961 (Map-case Flat File)